

# **Adrian Boscu**

**Date of birth:** 03/03/1987 | (+40) 746277867 | (+420) 777876728 |

adrian@boscu.ro https://www.linkedin.com/in/adrian-alexandru-boscu/

Czechia

About me:

A highly motivated, due-diligent and results focused CyberSecyrity analyst and Senior Network Security Consultant who has 14 years of professional cross-industry experience, primarily within information technology services. Experienced in advising clients and executives, planning and delivering cutting edge network solutions to global businesses, ensuring best practices within network architecture and configuration, using an analytical approach to problem solving, triaging and resolving complex and high impact issues with due-diligence, improving general IT services and exceeding expectations set by colleagues and leaders.

## WORK EXPERIENCE

02/2022 - 09/2022 - Barcelona, Spain

#### **NETWORK SECURITY CONSULTANT - NTT BARCELONA**

As part of the team in the NTT project in Barcelona, I was responsible for providing networking operational services for their EU restricted customers. As part of the team, I was responsible for jumpstarting the team from a technical perspective as well as providing guidance in operational and day to day activities. At the same time I was responsible for delivering and maintaining solutions for different network parts such as Security, Routing and Switching, Load balancing, DHCP/DNS, Wireless, and many more.

As part of primary duties and responsibilities were as follows:

- Troubleshoot and diagnose manufacturing site-specific issues
- Troubleshoot and diagnose end-user office issues ranging from blocked websites, wireless topics, and many more.
- Create new documentation and update new ones, as well as create new processes and procedures.
- Provide technical and procedural guidance for all the L1-L2 engineers
- Act as an escalation point for lower tiers engineers.
- Cisco ASA, CheckPoint and F5 SME for the project.

Technologies vendors and products part of this project:

Cisco routers/switches/firewalls, Checkpoint Firewalls, F5, Juniper, Palo Alto.

08/2021 - 05/2022 - Bruxelles, Belgium

**SENIOR NETWORK & CYBERSECURITY ENGINEER –** FUJITSU PROVIDING SERVICES FOR EEAS (EUROPEAN EXTERNAL ACTION SERVICE)

Working as part of the team supporting and deploying new projects for EEAS (European External Action Services) HQ and Delegations. As a Senior System Administrator in the project team we cover multiple tasks requested by the EEAS such as:

- End-to-end Implementation of architected solutions following a Low-level design provided by the architects
- Offer support and technical consultancy for ongoing projects.
- Implementation of changes related to the delivery of various solutions as part of a project but following the ITIL processes
- Deliver quality and detailed documentation related to the implemented services which cover but are not limited to Installation and configuration Guides, Operational procedures, various other services related mandatory documentation
- Drafting operational guidelines, procedures, installation notices, and scripts for the integration, installation, and upgrade of aforementioned component services;
- Perform knowledge transfer, service handover to operations and offer assistance with the roll-out of new ICT infrastructure projects;
- Operate following the defined ITIL processes and procedures;

- Intervention on ICT infrastructure (routers, switches, firewalls, F5 LB, etc);
- Development of scripts for automation of tasks and deployments

#### Technologies vendors and products part of this project:

Cisco ACI, Cisco routers/switches, Aruba Networks, Palo Alto NGFW, Panorama, Splunk

09/2020 - 12/2021 - Prague, Czechia

## CYBERSECURITY NETWORK CONSULTANT - HCL PROVIDING SERVICES FOR NOVARTIS

Assist remote production sites in remediating vulnerabilities as well as creating improvement strategies for application

and infrastructure hosted on-site. Minimize downtime for implementation and assist in integrating the local site in the

global security policies, standards, and frameworks.

- Analyze High-Level Remediation/Recommendation Plan provided for 3rd part security consultant services to make sure that they are feasible and understandable
- Investigating, designing, planning, and implementing communications networks
- Responsible for cybersecurity availability and planning such as backup and restore and disaster recovery.
- Perform risk and vulnerability assessment applied for OT on GxP environment.
- Drive any specific issues alongside SOC team as part of IRT group.

## Technologies vendors and products part of this project:

Cisco routers/switches/firewalls, Palo Alto NGFW, Panorama, Splunk

#### CyberSecurity methodologies and tools:

NIST, OWASP, ISO27000&ISO27001, Qualis, Nesus

02/2020 - 09/2020

#### CYBERSECURITY NETWORK CONSULTANT - THE ADECCO GROUP

As part of this project, I was responsible for providing consultancy in assessment and remediation activities needed

on the Global Adecco group environment which was hosting critical applications for the business. I was also responsible for defining strategy planning as well as remediation planning to ensure business continuity and security

for a continuously developing business.

- Ensure that applications/solution and their components (databases, web services, etc.) use a restrictive and accurate set of Firewall rules to allow network traffic only for applications, ports, IPs, and necessary protocols.
- Ensure that applications/solution and infrastructure components are placed in the correct zones in our environment in order to segregate the risky high data, reduce the attack surface, and improve security
- Perform and define cybersecyrity standards as part of the Security Governance team by defining specific internal processes and procedures as per industry standards (NIST, OWASP, ISO27000 and ISO27001 etc.)
- Analyze High-Level Remediation/Recommendation Plan provided for 3rd part security consultant services to make sure that they are feasible and understandable
- Partnering with application owner and other peers to develop a detailed implementation plan.
- Investigating, designing, planning, and implementing communications networks
- Preparing network schematics to define and illustrate network design solutions
- Submit Change request that will be executed for 3rd party vendor
- Perform risk assessments and vulnerability management activities as part of the application assessments as well as manage and track any specific vulnerability and risk management lifecycle.
- Participate with Stakeholders in system security lifecycle and design processes, concepts, methods and tools.
- Define and design cybersecurity standards according to existing industry cybersec standards (ISO27000/ISO27001, NIST, OWASP)
- Participate in Audits

## Technologies vendors and products part of this project:

Cisco routers/switches/firewalls, Palo Alto NGFW, Panorama, Splunk

CyberSecurity methodologies, frameworks and tools:

02/2019 - 01/2020

#### **SENIOR NETWORK CONSULTANT - NTT**

As part of the team in the NTT project, I was responsible for providing networking operational services for BMW, one of the biggest customers of NTT. As part of the team, I was responsible for delivering and maintaining solutions for different network parts such as Security (proxy and firewall), Routing and Switching, Load balancing, DHCP/DNS, Wireless, and many more. As part of primary duties and responsibilities were as follows:

- Troubleshoot and diagnose manufacturing site-specific issues
- Troubleshoot and diagnose end-user office issues ranging from blocked websites, wireless topics, and many more.
- Create new documentation and update new ones, as well as create new processes and procedures.
- Provide technical and procedural guidance for all the L1-L2 engineers
- Act as an escalation point for lower tiers engineers.
- BlueCoat Proxy and F5 SME for the project.

## Technologies vendors and products part of this project:

Cisco routers/switches/firewalls, BlueCoat Proxy, F5, Cisco ACI, Splunk

Address Prague, Czechia

04/2018 - 01/2019 - Prague, Czechia

#### **CYBERSEC ANALYST - HCL PROVIDING SERVICES FOR NOVARTIS**

As part of the team in Novartis, we were responsible for analyzing and onboarding new applications that are

considered Crown Juels and critical for the business into a new, more secure environment called RingFencing.

The primary responsibilities of the role were:

- Assist in vulnerability assessment and gap recognition of the application
- Create an onboarding plan and strategy for the application into the new environment
- Assist in migrating the assets and creating proper application id into the PaloAlto Firewalls and F5 WAF.
- Troubleshoot and support migration issues, if any, alongside the application team.
- Participate in RFP creation and vendor selection for the operation of the solution designed.
- Lead, define and implement vendor security and ensure security standards are applied by the vendor conforming to existing GxP environment.

## Technologies vendors and products part of this project:

PaloAlto NGF, PaloAlto LightCyber, Cisco Routers/Switches, BiglP-F5 (WAF), Splunk

**CyberSecurity methodologies and tools:** 

NIST, OWASP, ISO27000&ISO27001, Qualis, Nesus

Address Prague, Czechia

01/2017 - 03/2018 - Prague, Czechia

#### **TECHNICAL TEAM LEAD - AMAZON**

As part of the team in Amazon, I was responsible for being an escalation point from a process/technical perspective for all our team members and managing high severity call leading and driving issues to a fast resolution for reduced customer-facing impact.

#### Responsibilities:

- Develop and keep documentation updated
- Troubleshoot and document complex issues/problems
- Contribute to the operation of our customer environments
- Maintaining and developing the operation environment within my technology area(s).
- Contributing to optimization initiatives

- Planning and execution of own tasks in the networking segment
- Personal development, i.e., recommending and taking responsibility for private business, competency and development targets and activities.

## Technologies vendors and products part of this project:

AWS, Cisco Meraki, Cisco ASA, DNS/DHCP

Address Prague, Czechia

07/2014 - 12/2016

## **OPERATION SPECIALIST - NNIT**

As part of the networking team, I managed and maintained different vendor networks such as Paloalto, Cisco, and many more. I provided support to various infrastructures for several Danish customers, including GxP and Pharma customers. I maintained and troubleshot different technologies addressing various fields from wireless to routing, load balancing, and security.

#### Responsibilities:

- Contribute to the operation of our customer environments
- Maintaining and developing the operation environment within your technology area(s).
- Contributing to optimization initiatives
- Planning and execution of own tasks
- Personal development, i.e., recommending and taking responsibility for private business, competency, and development targets and activities.
- Develop and keep documentation updated

#### Networking:

- Maintaining and troubleshooting Paloalto firewalls
- Troubleshoot two ways authentification factors (SMS Passcode)
- o DNS, DHCP
- Switching: VLANs, Private VLANs, VTP, STP
- Routing: EIGRP, OSPF, BGP
- Security & NAT rules, site-to-site, and Remote Access VPNs, DMVPN (ASA)
- Redundancy: EtherChannels, HSRP, VRRP
- Load-balancing solutions (CISCO)
- Network monitoring: Syslog, SNMP; HP NNMI
- Cisco Wireless (Access Points and Wireless Domain Controller)

### Technologies vendors and products part of this project:

Cisco Switches/Routers/Firewalls/Wireless, PaloAlto NGFW, F5 LTM, DNS/DHCP

**Business or Sector** Information and communication | **Address** Praha, Czechia

10/2011 - 06/2014

#### **2ND LEVEL NETWORK ENGINEER - AT&T**

As part of the networking team, I was in charge of incidents resolution and change implementation for French Customers and IBM France Bluesky Project. At that time, IBM Bluesky counted more than 100 french customers having their distinctive networks, and on a day-to-day basis, I was in charge of maintaining and troubleshooting any problem within those networks. Working with such large networks implies working with Partners such as NCR to replace faulty equipment or ISP to solve particular WAN issues. Thanks to my communication skills, I was also the bridge between technical and non-technical team segments.

## Networking:

- Advanced knowledge load-balancing solutions (BigIP F5)
- Advanced knowledge of security & NAT rules, site-to-site and Remote Access VPNs (ASA, Checkpoint)
- DNS/DHCP
- Switching: VLANs, Private VLANs, VTP, STP
- · Routing: EIGRP, OSPF
- Redundancy: EtherChannels, HSRP, VRRP, Checkpoint ClusterXL solution, Nokia IP cluster
- Bluecoat PacketShaper and PolicyCenter products
- Bluecoat ProxySG solution
- Network monitoring: Syslog, SNMP, Vitalnet Suite

#### Technologies vendors and products part of this project:

Cisco Switches/Routers/Firewalls, Checkpoint Firewalls, F5 LTM, BlueCoat Proxy, DNS/DHCP

Address Brno, Czechia

11/2010 - 09/2011

#### 2ND LEVEL IT SPECIALIST, SECURITY SPECIALIST - IBM

As a 2nd level security analyst, the primary responsibility was to verify that all the equipment under our scope was compliant with IBM's vast set of security standards. This ensured that all equipment under our responsibility was up to date with our internal policies and industry standards in terms of security. At the same time, the team operating them had good practice standards in configuring the mentioned network devices

I correlated data repositories, process descriptions, and configuration management to discover compliance issues and escalate as needed. At the same time, I was creating reports (weekly or monthly) according to working instructions or on-demand, analysing root cause for bad results while escalating and tracking the resolution. Create TCP/IP scan reports and provide them to the Delivery Project Executive.

Address Brno, Czechia

#### EDUCATION AND TRAINING

31/03/2020 – CURRENT – London, United Kingdom MCS CYBERSECURITY – University of Essex

Address London, United Kingdom | Website https://online.essex.ac.uk

14/03/2016 - 30/04/2020 - California, United States

COMPUTER SCIENCE, 4 YEARS - BACHELORS DEGREE (BS) - University of The People

Address California, United States | Website <a href="https://www.uopeople.edu">https://www.uopeople.edu</a>

28/02/2022 - 06/03/2022 - Bruxelles, Belgium

**CISCO ACI - EEAS** 

Address Bruxelles, Belgium

31/05/2018

PCNSE COURSE - Extelligence

Prague, Czechia

PALOALTO FIREWALL 8.0 AND FIREWALL 7.1 - NNIT

Address Prague, Czechia

Brno, Czechia

**CHECKPOINT BASIC & ADVANCED - AT&T** 

Address Brno, Czechia

#### Address Brno, Czechia

Brno, Czechia

**CISCO ASA/PIX BASIC - AT&T** 

#### Address Brno, Czechia

12/2013 - 06/2014 - Brno, Czechia

## **3RD LEVEL MENTORING PROGRAM - AT&T**

Focus on individual training and labs so that the trainee will reach as fast and efficient as possible the potential 3rd level position in the company.

- training on logical path taken in troubleshooting an incident.
- training on communication and attitude in conference calls with customers or remote partners.
- training on providing simple and transparent explanation of an issue to non-technical people.

#### Address Brno, Czechia

## PROJECTS

## **Projects**

Developed my own Infrastructure network (Lab environment) based on ESXi 6.5 Hypervisor on a HP DL360 G7 server containing the following:

- 20xCSR1000v routers used for simulating different environments scenarios from ISP to LAN testing different routing protocols (BGP, OSPF, EIGRP)
- 2xBIGIP F5 LTM with 3 web servers for load balancing lab with 90 days trial license
- 2xASAv firewalls
- 2x Checkpoint R77.30 firewalls with one R77.30 SmartCenter
- VCenter 6.0 Appliance for managing and manipulating VMs
- Windows Server 2012 R2 used for DNS DHCP and AD
- 2x PaloAlto Firewall.
- 1x PaloAlto 220 Physical Firewall.

#### CERTIFICATIONS

Palo Alto Networks Certified Network Security Administrator (PCNSA)

**Amazon Web Services Practitioner (AWS Practitioner)** 

ITIL v4 Foundation

**Cisco Certified Network Associate (CCNA)** 

**Cisco Certified Network Professional (CCNP)** 

#### SKILL SUMMARY

## Skill Summary

## **Networking & Security**

Cisco Routing, Switching and Security (CCIE / CCNP Level), Wireless (CCNA Level), Cisco Meraki, Cisco ISE, ACI Checkpoint FW Palo Alto NGFW Load balancing - F5 LTM/GTM; Cisco ACE, Bluecoat Proxy Mikrotik Router board / wireless

#### **Operating Systems**

Linux (Ubuntu, Centos, OpenSuse) Windows Server 2012 Mac

## **Storage**

Synology

#### **Cloud & Virtualization**

AWS (Practitioner – studying for Associate Solution Architect)
DigitalOcean
OpenStack
VMware (VSphere & VCenter)

## Monitoring

PRTG - monitoring tool Nagios

## **Programing languages**

Python Swift

# **MOTIVATIONAL TARGETS**

#### **Motivational targets**

- continuous improvement in the professional activity
- working in a dynamic and competitive environment and with good perspectives, in a multicultural environment
- being a part of a motivated and determined team
- learning new things and getting the optimum combination with the personal skills

| ∘ finding new career opportunities |  |  |  |
|------------------------------------|--|--|--|
|                                    |  |  |  |
|                                    |  |  |  |
|                                    |  |  |  |
|                                    |  |  |  |
|                                    |  |  |  |
|                                    |  |  |  |
|                                    |  |  |  |
|                                    |  |  |  |
|                                    |  |  |  |
|                                    |  |  |  |
|                                    |  |  |  |
|                                    |  |  |  |
|                                    |  |  |  |
|                                    |  |  |  |
|                                    |  |  |  |
|                                    |  |  |  |
|                                    |  |  |  |
|                                    |  |  |  |
|                                    |  |  |  |
|                                    |  |  |  |
|                                    |  |  |  |
|                                    |  |  |  |
|                                    |  |  |  |
|                                    |  |  |  |
|                                    |  |  |  |